voteplz.org 2016-10-23

# Privacy Policy • voteplz

Last Revised: September 28, 2016 

This website is operated by VotePlz, Inc. ("VotePlz", "we" or "us"). This privacy policy ("Policy") explains how personal information is collected, used, and disclosed by VotePlz with respect to your use of the www.voteplz.org Web site and other VotePlz Web and mobile sites and applications which display this Policy (the "Sites") so you can make an informed decision about using the Sites. This Policy also applies to personal information collected on other web sites and mobile sites on our behalf by third party vendors. We reserve the right to change the provisions of this Policy at any time. We will alert you that changes have been made by indicating on the Policy the date it was last updated. We encourage you to review this Policy from time to time to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used. 

As used herein, the term "personal information" means information that specifically identifies an individual (such as a name, address, telephone number, mobile number, e-mail address, or credit card number) and information about that individual or his or her activities that is directly linked to personally identifiable information. Personal information does not include "aggregate" information, which is data we collect about the use of the Sites or about a group or category of services or users, from which individual identities or other personal information has been removed. This Policy in no way restricts or limits our collection and use of aggregate information. 

VotePlz collects personal information in order to help our users register to vote, request mail-in ballots and get to the polls, and to provide other voting-related tools and services. When you register to vote, check your registration status, order your absentee ballot, join our newsletter, or take any other action on this Site, we may ask you to give us contact information, including your name, address, email address and telephone number. We may also obtain information about you from outside sources and combine it with the information we collect through this Site. We use this information to operate this Site, to sends you news and information about VotePlz, to measure the effectiveness of our programs, and to send you timely election reminders. You may opt-out of receiving messages from VotePlz by sending any email to help@voteplz.org and asking that you not receive future email messages. You may also opt-out by following the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email. 

After you mail in or electronically submit your voter registration application form to local or state election officials, it generally becomes a matter of public record from your state of residence. This means it may be available for inspection and use by candidates for public office and their campaign organizations as well as by others who satisfy the requirements of the State law governing its use. 

If you have any questions about our security practices or this policy, please contact us at help@voteplz.org. Please read below for our complete privacy policy, and check this page periodically for alterations or amendments – we will occasionally modify this policy in order to ensure that it contains current information about our privacy practices, and we will maintain the version history on this page. 

Do not use this site or provide us with information if you do not agree with all of the terms. 

Information we gather 

When you register for an account or use VotePlz to fill out a voter registration or ballot request form, we do store personally identifiable information, including your name, postal address, email address, phone number, username, password, demographic information (such as your gender and occupation), and other identifying information. 

Information you provide will be used primarily to provide you with voter services (“Services”) according to your request. For example: 

  * If you sign up for election reminders, we use your contact information to send you a text message or email about upcoming elections in your district. 
  * If you sign up to receive a voter registration form or ballot request form, we use your information to generate and mail you the appropriate form. 
  * To provide the services, products, or information you request, and to process and complete such requests and any related transactions; 
  * To send you confirmations, updates, alerts, and support and administrative messages and otherwise facilitate your use of, and our administration and operation of, the Sites; 
  * To notify you about important changes to the Sites; 
  * To remind you to send in your voter registration form and to vote; 
  * To assist you in finding your registration information and polling location; 
  * To request feedback and to otherwise contact you about your use of the Sites; 
  * To respond to your emails, submissions, questions, comments, and requests and to provide customer service; 
  * To serve ads, on this or other websites or media, based on the information you provide and the actions you take; and 
  * For any other purpose for which the information was collected. 

VotePlz uses Google Analytics and similar analytics tools and services to monitor user traffic and visitor trends on the VotePlz website. When you visit the VotePlz website, we record basic information such as your IP address, referral source, browser type, and the date and time of your visit. 

Cookies and Data Tracking 

In order to better serve our supporters, we use cookies and web beacons, and periodically analyze web logs. Some cookies are used to pre-populate forms for you so that on repeat visits to the Site you don’t need to re-enter certain information. You can set your browser to disable cookies, but then you would not have the advantage of having certain sections of forms being pre-populated for you, and you may not be able to access certain parts of the Site. We may also use third-party services such as Google Analytics. This helps us understand traffic patterns and know if there are problems with our Site. We may also use embedded images in emails to track open rates for our mailings, so that we can tell which mailings appeal most to VotePlz supporters. 

The information generated by a cookie about your use of our Site (including your IP address) is transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where Google is legally required, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google can combine your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this Site, you consent to the processing of data by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. 

URLs contained in emails may contain an ID that enables us to correctly identify the person who takes an action using a web page. We use these URLs to simplify the process of signing petitions and filling out surveys. We may occasionally present a shortened URL that references a longer URL which you can see in the browser’s address bar when you access the page. 

Disclosure of Information 

We may disclose personally identifiable information about you to third parties in limited circumstances, including: (1) with your consent; or (2) when we have a good-faith belief it is required by law, such as pursuant to a subpoena or other judicial or administrative order. 

If we are required by law to disclose the information that you have submitted, we will attempt to provide you with notice (unless we are prohibited) that a request for your information has been made in order to give you an opportunity to object to the disclosure. We will attempt to provide this notice by email if you have given us an email address, or by postal mail if you have entered a postal address. If you do not challenge the disclosure request, we may be legally required to turn over your information. 

In addition, we will independently object to requests for access to information about users of our site that we believe to be improper. 

Third-party Service Providers 

VotePlz works with third party service providers and partners to send you forms and reminders, and to otherwise assist us in providing our service to you, and we transmit your information them for these purposes. We do not share any information with these service providers or partners beyond what is necessary to provide you with their services. 

We do not sell your information. As of the date of this privacy policy September 2, 2016, our third party service providers and partners with whom we share your information are: 

  * **SmartyStreets** : SmartyStreets helps us map your address and ensure that your forms get delivered by the USPS 
  * **Mailchimp** : we rely on Mailchimp to send you email reminders and notifications 

Our third party service providers and partners may change from time to time, and we will endeavor to update the list on our privacy policy promptly after any such change. If you have any questions about how we, or any of our service providers or partners, use your information, or if you would like to know if we have made any changes to our service providers or partners since the date of this privacy policy, please contact us at help@voteplz.org. We are not responsible for the actions of any service providers or other third parties, nor are we responsible for any additional information you provide directly to any third parties, and we encourage you to become familiar with their privacy practices before disclosing information directly to any such parties. Nothing herein restricts the sharing of aggregated or anonymized information, which may be shared with third parties without your consent. 

VotePlz Partner Organizations 

If you're signing up via one of our partners, this partner also has access to your personal data and general information about the services we provide you, and may contact you separately if you opt in to email or SMS communication. Our partners are committed to your privacy and do not sell your information. 

Links to other sites 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to ANY external links or any website not owned and operated by VotePlz. Third party sites will have their own policies which may be different from ours and we recommend that you check the privacy policy of each site that you visit. 

Advertising 

We may place online advertising with third-party vendors, including Google, which will be shown on other sites on the internet. In some cases, those third-party vendors may decide which ads to show you based on your prior visits to the Site. At no time will you be personally identified to those third-party vendors, nor will any of the personal information you share with us be shared with those third-party vendors. If you prefer to opt out of the use of these third-party cookies on the Site, you can do so by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt out page. 

Security 

VotePlz uses industry-standard security measures to protect the information you provide to us. Information you submit is encrypted through a Secured Socket Layer (SSL) connection, which protects the data in transit. We also encrypt all communication with our mail services provider to ensure that your data remains secure when transmitting voter forms to be printed. 

We take reasonable measures to protect your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware, however, that despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and no method of data transmission that can be guaranteed against any interception or other type of misuse. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. You are responsible for all uses of our web sites by any person using your password. Please advise us immediately if you believe your password has been misused. VotePlz shall not be responsible for any harm that you or any person may suffer as a result of a breach of confidentiality of any information you transmit to theVotePlz site. 

Updating or Removing Your Information 

You may choose to correct, update, or delete the user information you have submitted to us. However, please understand that deleted information may persist in our backup files. Also, changes to information do not affect information provided to others as set forth in this policy, including in connection with information that has been previously shared with like-minded organizations. 

Children’s Privacy 

VotePlz is intended for voting-age adults and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 years of age. If you are a parent or legal guardian of a child under age 13 who you believe has submitted personal information to us, please contact us immediately at help@voteplz.org. 

How to contact us 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you may contact us by sending an e-mail help@voteplz.org. You can also write to us at the following address: 

VotePlz   
335 Pioneer Way   
Mountain View CA, 94041
